Scot Itakura

scot.itakura@gmail.com | (909) 684-1552 Oakland, CA 94611 LinkedIn
https://www.linkedin.com/in/scot-itakura-289376157
Portfolio
https://scotitakuraportfolio.web.app
Github
https://github.com/scotitakura

Summary

Front-end web developer leveraging a background in geophysical data analytics and scientific coding programs to design and create unique, memorable, and dependable websites. Earth Science graduate from UC Santa Cruz and certificated Full-Stack Web Developer from UC Berkeley who is enthusiastic to enhance the quality of web applications by employing web development experience, analytical programming education, and passion to design, create, and innovate. Known as a strong team member for their ideas, efficiency, and congenial work atmosphere.

Technical Skills

React, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, Express, Styled Components, Materialize, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js Microsoft Excel, Python, SciPy, MATLAB, Geographic Information System (ArcGIS), STELLA

Projects

QualiTrees | https://github.com/scotitakura/QualiTrees | https://qualitrees-503dd.web.app/ Corporate Website

- Freelance solo project built with React for a start-up business to display products, information about the business, ways to contact, and frequently asked questions. Deployed with Firebase.
- Notable features include:
 - > Design that is aesthetic and complementary to the client's brand
 - ➤ Infinite and forward animations
 - ➤ Mobile responsiveness

Garage Collage | https://github.com/jennifermulder/garage-endeavor | https://garage-collage-2468.herokuapp.com/ *E-commerce Website*

- Held full responsibility for the front end of a three person group project. Built and created with React and styled using Styled Components, a fully functional garage sale e-commerce website was deployed with Heroku and completed within two weeks.
- Notable features include:
 - Complex and intriguing animations
 - > Seamless patterns used to create unique backgrounds
 - ➤ Mobile responsiveness

Work Experience

Information Technology Coordinator/Assistant Instructor

(Jan. 2020 – Present)

Ability Now Bay Area | Oakland, CA

- Tr Coordinator to help everyday computer, internet, hardware, software, and Zoom needs and education for the entire center.
- Educate and empower adults with disabilities and their families through advocacy, wellness, and building independence over online classes from the safety of their homes.

Staff Engineer

(July 2019 - Nov. 2019)

Berlogar Stevens & Associates | Pleasanton, CA

Support Project Managers with tasks associated with subsurface exploration including laboratory testing, construction monitoring and testing services during mass grading, foundation preparation, pile installation, and tieback installation.

Geotechnical Engineering Technician

(Sept. 2018 – June 2019)

Cornerstone Earth Group Inc. | Sunnyvale, CA

• Conduct geotechnical site observations of earthwork, utility backfill, drainage improvements, excavations, and foundation construction.

Education

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate
University of California, Berkeley

2020

University of California, Berkeley

(2014 - 2018)

Earth Science, Bachelor of Science University of California, Santa Cruz